Rae D. Cabello

DIRECTOR OF DESIGN

Contact: raedcabello@gmail.com | (210) 878.6681

PROFILE

I'm a Visual Designer from San Antonio, TX. I have a strong interest in all things design - this includes web, visual, development, packaging, branding and user experience. I have a special interest in typography, color theory, layout and composition.

I have over 10yrs of experience working as a visual and ux designer for small growing businesses, to large enterprise companies. I value people, product, experience, and quality over quantity. I enjoy breaking down problems and developing simple solutions to help create a great user centered experience that's naturally easy to understand and use no matter the platform or device.

REFERENCES

Chris Sandoval

USAA • Lead Digital Product Manager (512) 426.9500

Jarrett Washburn

Dell • Associate Experience Director (972) 849.5535

Agnes Czeblakow

UTSA • Archivist for Special Collections (972) 849.5535

EDUCATION

University of the Incarnate Word

2002 - 2003

Major: Jazz studies Minor: Art History

EXPERIENCE

July 2016 - Present Assembla Inc (San Antonio, Tx)

DIRECTOR OF DESIGN

Assembla is an award winning project management software company. My current responsibilities as Director of Design are company branding, UI/UX experience of both the front end and backend of the product, market positioning, design research, and content curation.

Aug 2010 - July 2016 Rackspace (San Antonio, TX)

SENIOR DESIGNER

Rackspace is a managed cloud computing company. My responsibilities were branding, ui/ux design, visual design - mainly around the "rackspace.com" marketing and development team. I received the 2015 Stevie Award for my contribution towards improving the customer self service experience.

Dec 2008 - Present Numero Group (Chicago, IL)

RESEARCHER, ARCHIVIST, DESIGNER

Numero Group is an 4x Grammy nominated archiving record label. My responsibilities are curation of music, research of music, and product design and layout for the Southwest Region of the US. My research and curation of

work have been mentioned in the New York Times and NPR.

2007 - 2010 Freelance Graphic Designer

BRANDING, PACKAGING, LOGO

Worked as a freelance designer with small businesses on branding of company and company products, menus, signage, and posters for major musical acts and record labels.

SKILLS

ILLUSTRATOR		USER RESEARCH	••••••
PHOTOSHOP	••••••	GOOGLE ANALYTICS	•••••
HTML CSS	•••••	SEO OPTIMIZATION	•••••
INDESIGN	••••••	CRITICAL THINKING	•••••
UI/UX	•••••		

AWARDS & RECOGNITIONS

2015 Stevie Award Winner: Web Service Solution category.

Co-designed a self-service support experience for customers looking to have easier access of self service tools and docs through the rackspace cloud control panel.